# PRAVEENKUMAR S

Date of Birth: 7<sup>th</sup> May 1991 #17, Royal Enclave
Mobile: 09964591103 9<sup>th</sup> Cross, 2<sup>nd</sup> Block, Akshay Nagar

E-mail: <u>kumarspraveen91@gmail.com</u>
Alternate Mobile: 07795636760

Bangalore – 560 016

KA, India

#### Profile:

I am a hardworking, highly proficient IT professional with 2+ years' experience and a real passion for mobile application development. Having helped develop a series of commercially successful apps on iOS. Having experience in Android mobile development, I am seeking a new opportunity that will allow me to further expand on these skills.

## **Skills Summary:**

- iOS and Android
- Objective-C
- SQLite

#### **Education:**

- 2012 till date Madurai Kamraj University, Hosur, TN M.C.A.
- 2008 2011 Thiagarajar College of Arts & Science, Madurai, TN. B.Sc (Information Technology)
- 2006 2008 V.H.N.Hr.Sec.School, Madurai, TN. H.S.C. Computer science, Accountancy
- 2005 2006 A.V.Hr.Sec.School, Madurai, TN. S.S.L.C Maths, Science

#### **Employment History:**

#### Adodis Technologies Pvt Ltd.,

iOS Application Developer

June 2012 - Present

- Used native Objective-C to develop state-of-the-art mobile applications for iOS.
- Involved at every project phrase, from concept creation to app store deployment.
- Responsible for general maintenance of application library and debugging.
- Developed applications with the compatible iOS development.
- Tested applications on device simulators and actual devices to fine-tune products.
- Supported junior members of the team, providing ongoing advice and guidance.

# Adodis Technologies Pvt Ltd.,

Android Application Developer

June 2011 – May 2012

- Involved in full product life cycle from design and development to deployment.
- Observed best practice standards in Android.
- Worked with offline based applications.
- Developed applications with Eclipse and ADT Plugins (up-to versions 3.0)

### **Assignments:**

Project #1 Cheeze Radio

Customer ATX Corporation Ltd.,

Project Description Streaming Live Radio and listing DJ's places from Thailand.

Developed Version -1.0.0 - 1.0.3

App Support iPhone App

App Store Link <a href="http://itunes.apple.com/in/app/cheeze-radio/id650796670?mt=8">http://itunes.apple.com/in/app/cheeze-radio/id650796670?mt=8</a>

Highlights • Streaming Live Radio and Live DJ

• Listing DJs with running Dj detail.

Project #2 TVMango

Customer ATX Corporation Ltd.,

Project TVMango is the application from house of Thailand to provide News, Video and lot of

Description categories.,

Developed Version – 1.0.0 to 1.0.2

App Support Universal

App Store Link http://itunes.apple.com/in/app/tvmango-thiwi-m-ng-ko/id720738641?mt=8

Highlights • Supports iPad compatibility.

• Streaming live tv and radio process.

• Video, Gallery, Schedule, Seminar and list of categories.

Project #3 Tata Communications Arsenal On The Go

Customer Tata Communications

Project Description A mobile based application providing overview of products and services on the move.

Developed Version -1.0.0 - 1.0.1

App Support iPhone App

App Store Link <a href="http://itunes.apple.com/in/app/tata-communications-arsenal/id594183821?mt=8">http://itunes.apple.com/in/app/tata-communications-arsenal/id594183821?mt=8</a>

Highlights • An application providing list of news services.

Supporting offline mode.

Project #4 Radio&TV TH Parl

Customer ATX Corporation Ltd.,

Project Description Radio&TV Th Parl is the application to present news from The Parliament

House of Thailand. Update the latest hot news, Live TV and Radio and etc., anywhere.

Developed Version – 1.0.1 to 1.2.1

App Support iPhone App

App Store Link <a href="http://itunes.apple.com/in/app/radio-tv-th-parl/id594476848?mt=8">http://itunes.apple.com/in/app/radio-tv-th-parl/id594476848?mt=8</a>

Highlights • Live TV streaming, Video categories and etc.,

• Supporting offline mode.

Project#5 VishalKapurDesign

Customer Vishal Kapur

Project VishalKapurDesign is an online shopping. Vishal has created a niche for himself by creating Description one of a kind ensembles conceptualised with experimental inspirations and unique layouts.

App Support iPhone App

App Store <a href="http://itunes.apple.com/in/app/vishalkapur/id785157844?mt=8">http://itunes.apple.com/in/app/vishalkapur/id785157844?mt=8</a></a>
Link

Highlights • Latest Products, Featured Products

• Category filtering and products Filtering. Search products

• Paypal Express Checkout & CCAvenue Payments.

Project #6 ShootnShare

Customer American Wedding Group

Project Application to provide the list of wedding anniversary which are going to held around the Description

user's current location with their informations.

App Support Universal

https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/the-pros/id859834960?ls=1&mt=8 App Store Link

Highlights Location & Bridegroom based informations.

Inviting Others to wedding

Project #7 Taxmann

Customer Taxmann

**Project** This application Displays the Top Stories at this hour of the latest update on Tax and

Corporate Laws. Description

Developed Version - 1.02 to 2.0.3

App Support iPhone App

http://itunes.apple.com/in/app/taxmann-app/id566257516?mt=8 App Store Link

Highlights Useful informations about Laws

Push notification for latest news